Preliminary Inventory of the Parviz Shokat collection
Hoover Institution Archives
Parviz Shokat collection
1954-2004
2012C31
Hoover Institution Archives
17 manuscript boxes (6.8 linear feet)
Serial issues, pamphlets, bulletins, newsletters, flyers, and leaflets issued by Iranian student groups abroad and leftist Iranian political groups in exile relating to political conditions and civil liberties in Iran, political opposition to the Pahlavi monarchy, and communist movements in Iran and among Iranians abroad.
Shokat, Parviz
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 2012.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Related Materials
Hamid Shawkat collection, Hoover Institution Archives
Iranian Political Opposition Literature collection, Hoover Institution Archives
Scope and Content of Collection
Serial issues, pamphlets, bulletins, newsletters, flyers, and leaflets issued by Iranian student groups abroad and leftist Iranian political groups in exile relating to political conditions and civil liberties in Iran, political opposition to the Pahlavi monarchy, and communist movements in Iran and among Iranians abroad.
Iran--Politics and government--1941-1979.; Iran--Politics and government--1979-1997.; Communism--Iran.; Civil rights--Iran.; Iranian students.; Iran--Emigration and immigration.
- Confederation of Iranian Students National Union (CISNU) and Iranian Student Association in the United States pamphlets, newsletters, and other printed matter, 1965-1983 (Boxes 1-5)
- Iranian socialist groups in Europe pamphlets and newsletters, 1968-1987 (Box 5)
- Setāreh Sorkh newspapers, 1972-1982 (Box 5)
- Jebhe-i Millī-i Irān (National Front of Iran) newsletters, 1972 (Box 5)
- Jebhe-i Millī-i Irān (National Front of Iran) printed matter, 1966-1981 (Box 6)
- Hizb-i Tudah (Tudeh Party) pamphlets, 1968-1978 (Box 6)
- Hizb-i Tudah (Tudeh Party) pamphlets and newsletters, 1972-1976 (Box 7)
- Communist Party of China, Persian translations of publications, 1964-1977 (Box 7)
- Sāzmān-i Inqilābī-i Hizb-i Tudah (Revolutionary Organization of the Tudeh Party) pamphlets, 1969-1978 (Box 8)
- Hizb-i Ranjbarān pamphlets and newsletters, 1980-1981 (Box 8)
- Sazman-i Inqilābīyun-i Kumūnīst (Marxist-Leninist) pamphlets, 1972-1974 (Box 9)
- Ittihād-i Kumunīst pamphlets, 1976-1977 (Box 9)
- Sāzmān-i Chirik'hā-yi Fadā'ī-i Khalq-i Irān (Organization of Iranian People's Fedaā'i Guerrillas) pamphlets and newsletters, 1972-1983 (Box 10)
- Sāzmān-i Mujāhidin-i Khalq-i Irān (People's Mojahedin Organization of Iran) pamphlets, 1972-1993 (Box 11)
- Sāzmān-i Mujāhidin-i Khalq-i Irān newspapers, 1972-1993 (Box 12)
- Sāzmān-i Mārxist-Leninīst Tufān pamphlets, 1969-1971 (Box 12)
- Nahzat-i Muqāvamat-i Millī monographs, 1982 (Box 12)
- Ittihād-i Mobārzeh dar Rāh-i Ijād-i Hizb-i Tabaqeh-i Kārgar pamphlets and journals, 1974-1975 (Box 12)
- Anjumān-i Islāmī Dānishjuyān dar Amrikā va Kānādā pamphlets, circa 1979 (Box 13)
- Jomhourī Khavahān Millī-i Irān journals, 1985 (Box 13)
- Sāzmān-i Mobārzeh Barā-yi Ijād-i Junbish-i Mustaqil Kārgarī pamphlets, 1980 (Box 13)
- Sāzmān-i Paykār dar Rāh-i Āzādī-i Tabaqeh-i Kārgar pamphlets, 1979 (Box 13)
- Shurā-yi Muttāhid-i Chap Barā-yi Dimukrāsī va Istiglāl pamphlets, undated (Box 13)
- Union of Iranian Students in the United States pamphlets, 1978 (Box 13)
- Hemat journals, 1973-1978 (Box 13)
- Pamphlets relating to Iranian politics, history, and society, 1975-1984 (Box 13)
- Pamphlets, monographs, and other printed matter relating to Iranian politics, history, and society, 1954-2003 (Box 14)
- Persian translations of works by Stalin, Lenin, and Mao, 1960-1973 (Box 14)
- Persian translations of works by Stalin, Lenin, Engels, and Mao, 1960-1978 (Box 15)
- Miscellaneous articles and newsletters issued by opposition groups, 1980 (Box 15)
- Newspapers and newsletters (Box 16)
  - 19 Bahman, 1350 [1971]
  - Edālat, 1357 [1978]
  - Ittihād-i Chap, 1358 [1979]
  - Iranian National Front, 1972, 1975
  - Iran Āzād, 1963-1975
  - Irānshahr, 1978-1979
  - Junbish-i Kārgarī, 1359 [1980]
  - Kār, 1358-1360 [1979-1981]
  - Kārgar, 1350-1353 [1971-1974]
  - Kayhān, 1973-1974
  - Khalq-i Musalman, 1358 [1979]
  - Marz-i Por Gohar, 1984
  - Nabarde, 1350 [1971]
  - Payām-i āzādi, 1362
  - Proletar, 1356-1357 [1977-1978]
  - Qyām Irān, 1356-1357 [1977-1978]
  - Rahā'ī, 1360 [1981]
  - Rastakhiz, 1353 [1974]
  - Miscellaneous, 1981-2004
- General articles and newsletters regarding Iranian opposition groups, 1971-1982 (Box 17)
- Sharon La Bere subject file, press release and petitions, 1971 (Box 17)